

# **Md Sanjid Hossain**

- sanjidds99@gmail.com
- +8801873967484
- ( Dhaka, Bangladesh
- (n) SanjidHossain

- (in) md-sanjid-hossain-00b153184
- https://sanjidhossain.super.site/
- (R<sup>6</sup>) Sanjid Hossain

## Profile

Specializing in Data Science, AI/ML engineering, Data analysis and QA engineering, with approximately 1 year of professional & 3 years of research experience complemented by practical skills in Data Analysis and ML Engineering. Recognized for unwavering work ethics, adeptness in meeting deadlines, and a steadfast commitment to continuous skill enhancement. Currently, expanding expertise into Software QA engineering to broaden contributions to the Software and Tech industry.

# **{}** Programing Language

Python — (Primary) | HTML/CSS | JavaScript | SQL/NoSQL | JAVA | C

## Skills

#### **Development Tool**

Flask, Streamlit, Gradio, GitHub, Render, MySQL, OOP, MVC, Bootstrap, Android Studio, 3utools, Linux, JIRA, Notion, ClickUp,

#### AI tools & Frameworks

FastAl, Pytorch, OpenCV, Scikit-Learn, Tensorflow, Chatbase, HuggingFace Spaces, ONNX, Blurr, YOLO, CNN, RNN, Transformer

#### **Database, Cloud & Networking tools**

MongoDB, Dbeaver, Oracle VM, AWS, Azure, Google cloud-Compute Engine, Charles, Fidler, Postman

#### **Data Analysis & Visualization Tools**

Tableau, Power BI, MS Excel, MS office, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly

# **Data Scaping & Automation Tools**

Selenium, Beautiful Soup, Scrapy, WebScraper.io

## Projects

### FoodLens Al

A complete web application built with flask that can recognize and classify foods, their Origins and The Restrictive Ingredients. The application can use both Image and Text from user and generate the result using multiple layers of AI models.

#### MultiLabel Article Classifier

A web application that can classify any form of News or article (complete or partial) from text (English) using ML model consisting of 18 categories.

### Data Analysis on Quality of Life 🛮

A complete data analysis project that uses population, GDP, Life expectancy and inflation rate data to determine the quality of life around the world & more detailed analys on multiple continents

# Professional Experience

## Intern QA engineer(Functional Testing), A1QA

07/2024 - present

- Worked on Multiple projects Including Websites, Mobile and Desktop Applications
- Developed and Report 300+ Issues on **JIRA** including genarating Report on **TestRails & Dashboard** creation.
- Experience on Creating Test Documentations, Test Survey, Acceptance Sheet
- Worked with API and Web encryption and Virtual machines including Cloud Services(AWS,Azure,GCloud)

# **Instructor,** Safenet Al

12/2023 - present

- work with ML, NLP, CV, Data scraping and vizualization
- Content and Research managment
- Project managment and research assistance

#### **Trainee Data Scientist,** *MasterCourse*

06/2023 - 10/2023 | Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Data Scraping, Collection, Data Analysis
- ML model training, API development & Deployment
- Al application Development & Deployment

### Intern Web Researcher (Remote), Klatch Technologies ltd.

08/2022 - 10/2022 | India

- Data quality assurance tests.
- · Research on web and data annotations

## Education

## **BSc in Computer Science & Engineering,**

Daffodil International University 2018 – 2022 | Dhaka, Bangladesh 3.41 out of 4.00

# Canguages

**Bengali** | **English** − 7,IELTS

### **References**

**Nasrin Akter**, *Data Engineer*, Microsoft akternasrin87@gmail.com

**Sanzidul Islam**, *Senior Lecturer*, Daffodil International University sanjid.cse@diu.edu.bd

**Mohammad Sabik Irbaz**, *Graduate Research Assistant*, George Mason University, VA, USA mirbaz@gmu.edu

## **Achievements**

# **ICPC International Collegiate Programing Contest** 2020

Participated in Inter-university Programing Contest held in Dhaka region

# **Take-off Programming Contest**

2019

Placed in top 20 on C Language base Intra-university Programing Contest.

## **■** Publications

Refining Bengali Hate Speech Detection: Multi-Label Classification Using RNN and LSTM, ICACTCE'24 (Springer Lecture Notes in Networks and Systems LNNS) (Accepted & processing)

# Road Condition Detection and Crowdsourced Data Collection for Accident Prevention: A Deep Learning Approach, 2023

Twelfth International Conference on Image Processing Theory, Tools and Applications (IPTA),France ☑ 10/2023

Hate Speech Detection Using Machine Learning In Bengali Languages, 2022 6th International Conference on Intelligent Computing and Control Systems (ICICCS) ☑ 05/2022